Bruno P. Kinoshita

Barcelona – Spain (UTC+1)

I have **20 years of experience** working in different industries such as telecommunications, banking, credit, retail, insurance, research, government, civil construction, and start-ups, with a **wide variety of roles** (developer, quality engineer, devops, architect, etc.). I program in Python, Java, JavaScript, PHP, and Shell Script. I am fluent in English and Portuguese. I have an intermediate level in Spanish and Japanese, and basic in French and Te Reo Māori.

Education

o Diploma in Business Administration, Mackenzie University 2008 – 2009 o BSc Information Systems, Mackenzie University 2003 – 2007

Experience

o Workflow Engineer @ BSC — Barcelona Supercomputing Center 09/2022 – actual

- Autosubmit Python development, part of Destination Earth Climate Digital Twins project (EU).

o **Software Engineer** @ *Curii* (*Remote NZ/EU/USA*) 12/2021 – 09/2022

- CZI grant to contribute to **CWL**, CWL Viewer, cwltool, documentation, and Outreachy mentorship.

o Research Software Engineer @ N/WA 10/2018 - 10/2021

- Cylc development, an Open Source workflow manager using JupyterHub, GraphQL, Python, Vue.js.

o Java Engineer @ *NIWA* 06/2017 – 09/2018

- Java JEE development on EcoConnect web services, used by Fire Services NZ, Māori TV, DOC-NZ.

o Full Stack Software Developer @ Spark Ventures 10/2016 – 06/2017

- **AWS** development, build systems, and Java development using **SpringBoot**.

o **DevOps** @ NIWA — National Institute of Water and Atmospheric Research 04/2015 - 09/2016

- Configuration management with Puppet and Ansible, automation, Java. Jenkins Cl.

o Senior Big Data Engineer @ Boa Vista Servicos (Equifax) 05/2014 – 03/2015

- Impala, HDFS, **Hadoop**. Cobol, Java. Development of the company first Big Data business cases.

o Senior Software Architect @ Tokio Marine 01/2013 – 05/2014

- ActiveMQ cluster, internal workshops, SSO, new Portal with Liferay. Company-wide KPI monitoring.

o Senior Infrastructure Engineer @ Tokio Marine 10/2012 – 12/2013

- Automation with **Jenkins** and **Puppet**.

o Senior Software Engineer @ Tokio Marine 10/2011 – 09/2012

- Java development with Servlets, Portlets, and LifeRay modules. SSO with OpenAM. Jenkins Cl.

o Senior System Analyst @ Lojas Riachuelo 07/2011 – 09/2011

- **Java Swing** development for retail POS system.

o Senior Software Quality Engineer @ Vivo (Telefonica) 01/2010 – 06/2011

- CRM development with Java and GWT. CI with Hudson, Sonar, Testlink, FishEye, and JIRA.

o Senior Software Engineer @ Nossa Caixa Bank 04/2008 – 12/2009

- .NET C# and Java support. Mainframes integration with Cobol, MQSeries, DirectConnect, Uniface.

o Junior System Analyst @ Claro 06/2007 - 03/2008

- Java web development and J2EE using Servlets, EJBs, JMS.

o Junior System Technician @ *Claro* 01/2006 – 05/2007

- **Java Swing** and J2EE development on the VAS middleware platform.

o Value Added Services intern @ Claro 07/2004 – 12/2005

- VAS middleware platform support, partner onboarding, marketing campaigns, billing integration.